good morning good morning oh there's no service oh you can't see me i mean okay now i can't it's
working it's getting there okay okay yeah sorry we're uh we're doing a media blitz right now
uh so it might look rainy we have a little bit of internet people using it to mess
out so apologies for the uh the bad reception blitz away all right yeah so we are currently
about 200 nautical miles off the coast of gaza so in 50 nautical miles we will be entering the red
zone which is historically where israeli the uh national waters uh ships and it and takes them
back with the military in the port of ashdod so uh we're going slow right now to hopefully go until
wednesday before we get intercepted uh but the sun sets here around 7 p.m it's currently 5 p.m local
time um we'll cross the line into the interdiction zone at about 4 a.m and uh hopefully the sun will
rise and have another day of sailing um we're gonna be on on watch tonight okay from what i gathered
from the um optimus prime audio um oh no
you're crossing over at around 4 a.m into what's considered the red zone
the red zone but you all are hoping that you'll still have another day of sailing before
they try to come through and intercept yes that's correct um i spoke to another uh member of the
flotilla this morning um iara modarelli and uh she was saying that essentially um israel was calling
embassies like saying that they wanted the right to be able to harm you all i mean what do you think
is is on their agenda at this point well first of all it's gone through a number of phases right you
know uh when we first launched when we first launched yet uh fire brands like ben gavir say you
know we were all going into long-term terror prisons in order to dissuade activists from ever
attempting anything like this again uh then we waged a comms war against the uh ministry of diaspora
who was open source intelligence
uh you know i've been told just back the report uh traced to the source
uh yeah to manufacture uh attack uh attack the flotilla and i would like to remind people that the
ministry of diaspora affairs is not an intelligence organization for it is literally a problem of the
israeli state who connected with the jewish diaspora and u.s politicians the ministry of diaspora affairs
recently spearheaded the um the 50 states one israeli campaign last week that took 200 of our
our representatives you know at state level and congressional level to um lobby them for anti-bds
laws here in the united states so um basically what we've seen their media messaging um kind of shift
from an attack to we're going to be and we're going to be sent to immigration jail and people who
have had offenses multiple times we'll be looking at long prison sentences and so they're calling
embassies to kind of the night before interdiction to test what they can get away with so nothing's
set in stone we're anticipating everything they're a rogue actor currently committing a genocide
um so nothing's off the table do you think there would be anything do you think it would be valuable
for folks to um protest at their embassies to raise the alarm around you all being protected would that even
matter i mean okay well first of all what happens to us doesn't really matter um you want people back
in the comments like what should we be doing well we would like you to do a little bit more than
existing on social media and spreading the word it's very important for awareness and education but you
will not have a better opportunity than a bunch of a u.s citizen and delegations from other countries
to leverage that politically in order to ensure the u.s government
so this means calling representatives uh this means writing emails this means showing up to town halls city halls embassies and uh engaging in direct action you know this flotilla
proving that it works look what the italians did i mean the the united states is not prepared at all for
that level of like organized labor action and it hasn't been since the vietnam war the u.s government
actually destroyed labor unions after that but there are a lot you can do um so basically that's kind of what
we're looking for parallel actions in conjunction with us so wednesday we're going to be a sale most
likely we're still going to be in prison on the weekend so yeah is when you get off work the weekend
where you can lobby and really do civil disabilities to be in prison so that's when everyone's more free
and has more time to do these kind of things so i got some advice i got you wait um yeah you said you
said here's something you said that's some advice or here's some advice no it's just buzz okay well we
um but that's really i know like that gives very clear guidance so thank you um what um what type of
what what are you guys doing to prepare for the for the uncertain inevitable well i mean the only thing
we have going for us is we're a complete non-violent civilian aid mission with no weapons and no hostile
hostile intent at all so but we are not weaponized but we are this we are not militarized we're on
old ancient sea hulks that can barely sail um and yeah that's the only protection we have is being
non-civilian non-combatants unfortunately we're going up against the state or encountering a state
that has a long and colorful history of assassinating and killing humanitarian aid workers
you know the most recent example is the world central kitchen convoy where they did a triple
uh tap strike on a bunch of you know european aid workers from the world central kitchen
who uh coordinated their movements they did it
and it works so that's kind of what we're concerned about and the only protection that we have
is all engagement what happens we have no diplomatic cover you know mike is our ambassador
who supports support right americans he didn't get it i just talked to i talked to chris smalls
before like we got on the boat to see what kind of consular support he received zero uh no military
no economic support yeah so the only support we're getting so you guys got nothing else going on this
weekend well we got a hobby for you oh god greg um last question for you um people want to know have
there been i know that um greece sent a boat but then it stayed in greece waters uh is spain still
sending a boat to escort you all a naval ship yeah they'll be they'll be here tomorrow they'll be
escorting us for a little bit but they will not cross into uh the interdiction zone yeah a lot of
this is performative but it's not insignificant okay because for the first but because for the first
time all of these um all these european states which are actually still in play politically in
terms of uh the context of palisade america will always support israel we will we will be dragged down
by that anchor into the depths but europe is still in play and what we've seen on this flotilla just
very small slow movements that put spain italy and turkey into conflict with the israeli government
in a way we haven't seen before so um a lot of uh media has been seeing um you know as time
before to ask uh is a self-recruise stuff uh but that's because they're in terms of their own like
journalistic epistemology activist movements can't move geopolitics the things that move geopolitics
are states and forums like the un davos g7 you know active is at best at biggest occupy wall street
which collapsed on the stall and that's really stupid or you know in the most minor level which
is great but still doesn't really you know like code uh but what we've done here is we've actually
engaged states in geopolitical issues and that doesn't happen before yet so um i personally think that no
matter what happens tomorrow night this has already been successful we just use sports references but
just move the ball for one yard at a time um and so i think i think it definitely has worked and we
definitely won the cops war uh against the ministry of diaspora affairs so i'm really proud of what's been
accomplished and we'll see how it ends but um we're gonna sail and they're gonna do whatever they're
gonna do i guess history will be our judge well we're here with you in in the many ways that we
can be and i agree that action has to be a part of the response not just being on here raising awareness
so i'm going to be repeating everything that you said uh because i do have the gift of translating
optimus prime audio so so i got you um so you know honestly greg i just i i really feel like you know
the veterans boat you should know i marched with the veterans to the uh to the u.n um protest on
tuesday i mean on friday and i thought of you i thought of you i was with uh the veterans about
face group and i was like oh this cracks people so uh but we are we are really here just so appreciative
and so inspired by the efforts that you guys have taken in this i mean y'all greg has been on this
boat for like three weeks i mean i spoke to you like two weeks ago okay hey four we're tender but
so we're pretty good
damn that was really bad okay say it one more time say it one more time
okay i'm sorry like we've been on this so long we're ready to go to prison i'm looking forward to it
you get it that's saying something that's saying yeah well we hope that that is not the outcome
we're all hoping for a miracle um which you know i'm i don't really be hoping for miracles like that
but in this case you know there's many that need to happen all at once and you guys yourselves are a
miracle just in really meeting the moment with action and understanding that your white bodies
are more valuable than anybody's in this in the climate that we're in so thank you
yeah well you know i'm kind of reactivating my gallows humor so um i guess in the context of you
know my my military service and this i've done dumber for worse reasons so let's get it done
yeah yeah well greg we'll be watching we'll be supporting we'll be raising our voices we'll be
out there protesting to make sure that these people do what they need to do to get you all home and
hopefully we don't need to do any of that because for some reason israel decides you know what fuck it
let them through so that's what we're hoping for and um we're watching all right here's no
credit until uh going on my instagram profile until they jam our satellite communications
all right so you all heard that you can keep up with what's going on with greg um and the flotilla
on his instagram as long as we can so we'll be there yeah thank you so much we're gonna keep watching
um all right yeah why did i salute why did i salute um okay so what greg was saying was that
ultimately just um the the flotilla is is a is a device that can be used as a diplomatic tool
to push our embassies across the world to respond in a way that they haven't been responding to
palestine directly and so think of it in basketball it's like a screen all right where it's like running
a screen and this is a very useful tactic because this is what people humanitarians are doing is putting
their american argentinian in um you know brazilian german swedish italian bodies in
the sight line of palestine and they're saying like you need to protect us because if israel's on the
other side and it's y'all we come from y'all you need to protect us and when we are here in those
countries we need to also be on the other side saying you need to protect them which by the way
is a proxy process of also challenging israel this is when we talk about strategy this is when we talk
about you know geopolitical movements on boards etc like we always see this being done for the
negative this is how we do this for the positive so when we talk about proxy wars what we're talking
about is when a country uses another country to fight a country that they don't want to fight
directly right so for instance like ukraine is being used in a proxy war against russia so that
the united states doesn't have to fight russia directly they're basically using ukraine to do so
right when we look at the congo when we look at sudan like the uae is using the sudanese fighters in a
proxy war against other nations that want to get their resources the same in the congo so we can apply
those same skills in a positive way we can be the proxies for palestinians so you don't want to
protect palestinians fine you got to protect us i'm a taxpayer i'm a citizen we're on a humanitarian
mission i am unarmed that is the pressure that is being put on these governments across the world
so now i hope you have a bit more of a context you know so i'm hoping that you guys heard i'm
hoping that if you are in any of these countries in any of these cities where you have members who
are on the global summit flotilla that you will be outside of their embassies and what greg was saying
was that they're going to be incarcerated you know or in arrested i should say um on thursday
which means they will still be in jail this weekend because yom kippur the jewish holiday is on friday
and so knowing that they will still be in prison this weekend they're saying
be out there this weekend if you can't protest during the week because you have work etc etc
fine but this weekend will still be locked up and you got time okay you got time so again i i am
forever grateful to the individuals who have set out in this mission you know when we look at history so
often we just see these big massive things that have taken place and we forget about all of the individual
efforts big and small that have had to happen in order to push in order to push change in order to
cause a rupture a rapture and a shift to happen so um i have stated what the call to action is very
clearly so at the end of this you can go back and watch i'm not sure why you are asking me that um as
far as embassies you like i said any embassies that are represent they have people that are on the
flotilla um you can be there and not only embassies but people you are in the united if you're in the
united states it's not embassies that you're going to it's going to be the offices and calling the offices
of your local state senators your local state representatives your governors as well as your congresspeople
right your senators and your house your representatives in the house of congress
so all of these things um are are calls to action literally calls to action so this is going on
it's happening this weekend um
you know when people say things like when are we going to get serious and stop working my question is
have you stopped working you see i think so many people are waiting for somebody to organize a
boycott are you paying your taxes do you are you saying that you require everybody to do it for you
to do it so that's the real thing right have you and your friends stopped working and figured out how
you and your group of people can support each other because even if four of you said all right we're
going on strike we're going to stop working and we're going to support each other then do that but
when y'all say when are we going to stop working you're essentially saying i'm not going to stop unless
everybody else stops and it never happens that way it always starts with a small group of people
having the balls to do the thing sometimes it starts with one person having the balls to do the thing
have and when i say balls i'm also referring to ovaries because they are round october 1st is the
global strike thank you nola october 1st is a global strike we should be striking every thursday
every thursday we shouldn't be spending any money any money on thursdays none but for what it's worth
if you're waiting for everybody you're going to be waiting a long time start organizing stop waiting
for an organizer come an organizer this is what i'm trying to explain to y'all
and a lot of people that you all think are leaders are not leaders you think they're leaders because
they have more followers you think they're leaders because they've been on tv because we've been tricked
to think that these people are leaders they're not leaders they're not and when i say leaders i don't
mean that they're better than you or you know that they're gifted than you more except i just mean some
people are able to bring the thing out of folks that needs to happen that's the leader they're able
to tap in that's the leader that doesn't mean they're the best at logistics that doesn't mean
that they're the best that even um that means that that doesn't mean they're the most patient but they
know the direction and they know how to get you to go in that direction that's the leader okay
so you got to ask yourself some of these people that you look at as leaders where are they leading you
where have they been leading you i made some oatmeal this morning and it is so nasty
and i'm so hungry so i have to go